Finding Aid for the Max Brand Stories LSC.1284
UCLA Library Special Collections
Max Brand stories
1917-1963
UCLA Library Special Collections
Brand, Max
LSC.1284
4.0 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
Frederick Schiller Faust (1892-1944), best known as Max Brand, was an author of western novels such as Destry rides again (1930), Singing guns (1938), and Danger trail (1940). He also wrote spy and crime novels under the pseudonyms Frederick Frost and Walter C. Butler including Calling Dr. Kildare (1940) and its sequels. The collection consists of stories clipped from pulp magazines written by Faust under his various pseudonyms.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Robert Easton, 1977.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 997094593606533
Biography
Frederick Schiller Faust was born in Seattle, Washington on May 29, 1892; best known as Max Brand, author of western novels such as Destry rides again (1930), Singing guns (1938), and Danger trail (1940); also wrote spy and crime novels under pseudonyms Frederick Frost and Walter C. Butler; wrote Calling Dr. Kildare (1940) and its sequels, and worked on films based on them; published poetry, The village street and other poems (1922) and Dionysus in Hades (1931); killed while a war correspondent for Harper's at Santa Maria Infante, Italy, May 12, 1944.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of stories written by Frederick Schiller Faust under his various pseudonyms: Max Brand, George Owen Baxter, Martin Dexter, John Frederick, Peter Moreland, David Manning, Evan Evans, George Challis, and Dennis Lawton. Most of the stories were clipped from pulp magazines.
Scope and Content
A collection of stories written for pulp magazines by Faust under his pseudonyms: Max Brand, George Owen Baxter, Martin Dexter, John Frederick, Peter Moreland, David Manning, Evan Evans, George Challis, and Dennis Lawton. The collection is arranged chronologically and many of the stories have been clipped out of various pulps.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Collection arranged chronologically.
Western stories.; American fiction -- 20th century.; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Faust, Frederick Schiller; Brand, Max, 1892-1944--Archives.; Faust, Frederick Schiller, 1892-1944--Archives.
- 1917-1921
  - 1917
    - The Gambler and the Stake. Short story. All-Story Weekly, April 28. (Box 1)
    - The Sole Survivor. Novelette. All-Story Weekly, September 15. (Box 1)
    - Dragon Teeth. Poem. All-Story Weekly, September 22. (Box 1)
    - The Sword Lover. Serial (incomplete, chapters 1-23). Argosy, November 10. (Box 1)
  - 1918
    - Silence. Poem. All-Story Weekly, April 27. (Box 1)
    - A Rendezvous with Death. Novelette. All-Story Weekly, May 18. (Box 1)
    - John Ovington Returns. Short story. All-Story Weekly, June 8. (Box 1)
    - Above the Law. Novelette. All-Story Weekly, August 31. (Box 1)
    - Bad-Eye, His Life and Letters. Short story. All-Story Weekly, October 19. (Box 1)
  - 1919
    - That Receding Brow. Novelette. All-Story Weekly, February 15. (Box 1)
    - That Laughter of Slim Malone. Short story. All-Story Weekly, June 14. (Box 1)
    - The Fear of Morgan the Fearless. Short story. All-Story Weekly, June 28. (Box 1)
    - It Was Like This---. Short story. All-Story Weekly, August 30. (Box 1)
    - The House that Steve Built. Short story. All-Story Weekly, September 27. (Box 1)
  - 1920
    - Pride of Tyson. Serial (incomplete, part 4 of 6). Argosy All-Story Weekly, July 24. (Box 1)
    - The Ghost. Short story. Argosy All-Story Weekly, July 24. (Box 1)
  - 1921
    - Donnegan. Serial (incomplete, chapters 37-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, April 16. (Box 1)
    - Jerico's Garrison Finish. Novel. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, May 21. (Box 1)
    - The Guide to Happiness. Serial (complete). Argosy All-Story Weekly, August 13, 20, 27, September 3, 10, 17. (Box 1)
    - Sheriff Larrabee's Prisoner. Novel. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, December 3. (Box 1)
- 1921-1924
  - 1921
    - Black Jack. Serial (complete). Argosy All-Story Weekly, December 10. (Box 2)
  - 1922
    - The Fugitive's Mission. Novel. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, January 14. (Box 2)
    - The One-Way Trail. Novel. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, February 4. (Box 2)
    - Three Who Paid. Serial (Incomplete, chapter 32-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, April 8. (Box 2)
    - The Shadow of Silvertip. Serial (incomplete, chapters 24-29, 38-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, June 17. (Box 2)
    - Slumber Mountain. Novel. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, July 8. (Box 2)
    - Old Carver Ranch. Serial (incomplete, chapters 1-6) Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, August 26. (Box 2)
    - Mountain Madness. Novel. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, August 26. (Box 2)
    - Joe White's Brand. Novel. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, October 14. (Box 2)
    - Without a Penny in the World. Novel. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, October 21. (Box 2)
  - 1923
    - Hired Guns. Serial (incomplete, chapters 6-10, 21-25). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, March 10. (Box 2)
    - Seven Trails to Romance. Serial (incomplete, part 1). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, September 1. (Box 2)
    - Wooden Guns. Serial (incomplete, chapters 30-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, September 15. (Box 2)
    - The Stranger at the Gate. Serial (incomplete, parts 1-3 of 6) Argosy All-Story Weekly, November 3, 10, 17. (Box 2)
    - The Whisperer of the Wilderness. Serial (incomplete, chapters 6-9, 17-22) Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, December 1. (Box 2)
  - 1924
    - Train's Trust. Serial (incomplete, chapters 39-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, January 26. (Box 2)
    - Argentine. Serial (incomplete, chapters 29-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, May 31. (Box 2)
    - The Gambler. Serial (incomplete, chapters 13-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, June 7. (Box 2)
    - The Love of Danger. Serial (incomplete, chapters 6-16, 23-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, August 2. (Box 2)
    - Larramee's Ranch. Serial (incomplete, chapters 1-6, 8-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, September 13. (Box 2)
    - Mountain Made. Serial (complete). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, December 13. (Box 2)
- 1925-1930
  - 1925
    - Fire Brain. Serial (incomplete, chapters 21-25, 34-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, September 12. (Box 3)
    - The White Cheyenne. Serial (incomplete, chapters 1-7, 15-21, 28-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, December 12. (Box 3)
  - 1926
    - Bluejay. Serial (incomplete, chapters 23-26). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, February 20. (Box 3)
    - The White Wolf. Serial (incomplete, chapters 13-17). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, March 6. (Box 3)
    - Acres of Unrest. Serial (incomplete, chapters 1-29). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, June 12. (Box 3)
    - Western Tommy. Serial (incomplete, part 1). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, July 24. (Box 3)
    - Trouble Trail. Serial (incomplete, chapters 29-end). Street & Smith's Story Magazine, August 28. (Box 3)
    - The Border Bandit. Novelette. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, September 25. (Box 3)
    - The Border Bandit's Indian Brother. Novelette. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, October 2. (Box 3)
    - The Border Bandit's Prize. Novelette. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, October 9. (Box 3)
    - The Iron Trail. Serial (incomplete, chapters 30-36). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, October 30. (Box 3)
  - 1927
    - Smiling Charlie. Serial (incomplete, chapters 23-29). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, February 12. (Box 3)
    - Pleasant Jim. Serial (incomplete, chapters 29-35). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, October 22. (Box 3)
  - 1928
    - The Path to Plunder. Serial (incomplete, chapters 23-29). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, March 17. (Box 3)
    - The Gun Tamer. Serial (incomplete, chapters 15-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, April 28. (Box 3)
    - The Brass Man. Serial (incomplete, chapters 23-29). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, June 23. (Box 3)
    - Silver Trail. Serial (incomplete, chapters 8-14, end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, October 27. (Box 3)
    - Singing Guns. Serial (incomplete, chapters 15-21). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, December 15. (Box 3)
  - 1930
    - Twelve Peers. Serial (incomplete, chapters 22-29). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, February 1. (Box 3)
    - Tiger's Den. Serial (incomplete, chapters 23-35, part 5). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, March 15, April 12. (Box 3)
    - The Golden Coyote. Short story. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, April 12. (Box 3)
    - Happy Jack. Serial (incomplete, part 1, chapters 1-7, 15-22, 37-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, April 26. (Box 3)
    - White Hunger. Short story. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, April 26. (Box 3)
    - The Stingaree. Serial (incomplete, part 1). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, June 7. (Box 3)
    - Back to His Own. Short story. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, June 7. (Box 3)
- 1930-1934
  - 1930
    - Rippon Rides Double. Serial (incomplete, chapters 37-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, October l8. (Box 4)
    - On Fortune's Back. Serial (incomplete, chapters 37-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, December 6. (Box 4)
  - 1931
    - Valley Vultures. Serial (incomplete, chapters 29-35). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, May 30. (Box 4)
    - The Rancher Returns. Serial (incomplete, chapters 6, 15-21). Street & Smith's Westeren Story Magazine, July 11. (Box 4)
    - Tramp Magic. Serial (incomplete, chapters 15-36). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, November 21. (Box 4)
  - 1932
    - Dogs of the Captain. Serial (incomplete, chapters 1-7, 23-25). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, January 2. (Box 4)
    - The Lightning Runner. Serial (incomplete, chapter 15-end). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, January 9. (Box 4)
    - Speedy--Deputy. Novelette. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, February 13. (Box 4)
    - Rancher's Legacy. Serial (complete). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, February 20. (Box 4)
    - Seven-day Lawman. Novelette. Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, February 27. (Box 4)
    - The Golden Spurs. Serial (incomplete, chapters 1-36). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, March 26. (Box 4)
    - Lucky Larribee. Serial (incomplete, chapters 1-29). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, April 2. (Box 4)
  - 1933
    - Montana Rides. Serial (complete). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, January 14. (Box 4)
    - The White Indian. Serial (complete). Argosy, September 9. (Box 4)
  - 1934
    - The Tough Tenderfoot. Serial (complete). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, February 3. (Box 4)
    - Brother of the Cheyennes. Serial (incomplete, parts 3-6 of 6). Argosy, March 31, April 7, 14, 21. (Box 4)
- 1934-1936
  - 1934
    - Valley of the Vanishing Men. Serial (complete). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, June 2. (Box 5)
    - Man of the West. Serial (incomplete, chapters 31-37). Street & Smith's Western Story Magazine, November 10. (Box 5)
    - The Firebrand. Serial (complete). Argosy, November 24, December 1. (Box 5)
  - 1935
    - Spy! The Case of the Strange Villa. Short story. Detective Fiction, January 5. (Box 5)
    - Spy! The Little Father of Death. Short story. Detective Fiction, January 12. (Box 5)
    - Spy! The Case of the Scarred Back. Short story. Detective Fiction, January 26. (Box 5)
    - The Great Betrayal. Serial (incomplete, parts 1, 3 of 3). Argosy, February 2, 16. (Box 5)
    - Spy! Wings Over Moscow. Short story (incomplete). Detective Fiction, May 11. (Box 5)
    - Spy! The Downfall. Short story. Detective Fiction, May 25. (Box 5)
    - Claws of the Tigress. Novelette (incomplete). Argosy, July 14. (Box 5)
    - The Blackbirds Sing. Serial (complete). Argosy, July 21, 27, August 4, 10, 17, 24. (Box 5)
    - The Bait and the Trap. Short story. Argosy, August 4. (Box 5)
    - The Sacred Valley. Serial (complete). Argosy, August 10, 17. (Box 5)
    - The Pearls of Bonfadini. Short story. Argosy, August 24. (Box 5)
- 1935-1937
  - 1935
    - Range Feud. Novel. Best Western Magazine, September. (Box 6)
    - The Dew of Heaven. Serial (incomplete, parts 1-2 of 6). Argosy, September 7, 14. (Box 6)
    - ---Murder Me! Serial (incomplete, part 5). Detective Fiction, October 9. (Box 6)
  - 1936
    - The Streak. Serial (incomplete, part 1 of 6). Argosy, January 25. (Box 6)
    - Big Game. Serial (complete). Argosy, May 9, 16, 23, 30, June 6, 13. (Box 6)
  - 1937
    - Viva! Viva! Short story. Argosy, January 2. (Box 6)
- 1937-1941
  - 1937
    - The American. Serial (complete). Argosy, February 27. (Box 7)
    - War For Sale. Serial (complete). Argosy, April 24, May 1, 8, 15. (Box 7)
    - The Smoking Land. Serial (incomplete, part 3 of 6). Argosy, June 12. (Box 7)
    - The Champion. Short story. All-American Fiction, November. (Box 7)
  - 1938
    - The Bells of San Carlos. Short story. Argosy, April 30. (Box 7)
  - 1939
    - Half a Partner. Short story. Blue Book Magazine, March. (Box 7)
  - 1940
    - The Firebrand. Serial (complete). Cavalier Classics, July. (Box 7)
    - Senor Solo. Novel. Crack-Shot Western, August. (Box 7)
    - The Ghost. Short story. Crack-Shot Western, August. (Box 7)
    - A Blade for Borgia. Novelette. Cavalier Classics, September. (Box 7)
  - 1941
    - The Sacking of El Dorado. Novelette. Crack-Shot Western, January. (Box 7)
- 1941-1953
  - 1941
    - The Man Who Goes Alone. Short story. Argosy, February 15. (Box 8)
    - Luck of the Spindrift. Serial (complete). Blue Book Magazine, April. (Box 8)
    - East Wind. Short story. Argosy, July 5. (Box 8)
  - 1949
    - Guns of the Lost Land. Novel. All-Story Western, January. (Box 8)
    - Hell Rides the Rio. Novel. All-Story Western, November. (Box 8)
  - 1951
    - Sleeper Turns Horsethief. Novelette. Max Brand's Western Magazine, September. (Box 8)
  - 1952
    - Wine on the Desert. Short story. Max Brand's Western Magazine, May. (Box 8)
  - 1953
    - A Watch in the Wilderness. Novelette. Max Brand's Western Magazine, January. (Box 8)
  - 1963
    - Hunted Riders. (3rd printing) Pocket Books, Incorporated. (Box 8)